SpongeBob Squarepants: Kreepaway Kamp is a tv movie,
family, comedy film directed by Dave Cunningham.
While at Kamp Koral for a reunion, SpongeBob and the gang are stalked by a mysterious
figure lurking in the shadows as campers start disappearing one by one!
SpongeBob / Cabin / Clam / Snail / Tall Tail / Vampire Monster / Sea
Urchins / Jellyfish / Anchovies (voice), played by Tom Kenny.
Patrick / Anchovy #2 / Roh / Sea Urchins / Anchovies
(voice), played by Bill Fagerbakke.
Squidward / Regigilled / The Creeper / Sea Urchins
(voice), played by Rodger Bumpass.
Mr. Krabs / Anchovies (voice), played by Clancy Brown.
Sandy / Rea / Teen Girls / Sea Urchins / Anchovies
(voice), played by Carolyn Lawrence.
Plankton / Larry the Lobster / Anchovy #1 / Sea Bunnies /
Sea Urchins (voice), played by Mr. Lawrence.
SpongeBob SquarePants is an American animated television series created by marine biologist
and animator Stephen Hillenburg that premiered on Nickelodeon on May 1, 1999.
The series is set in the fictional underwater city of Bikini Bottom, and centers on the adventures
and endeavors of SpongeBob SquarePants, an enthusiastic and optimistic sea sponge.
Many of the ideas for the show originated in an unpublished, educational comic book
titled The Intertidal Zone, which Hillenburg created in the mid-1980s.
He began developing SpongeBob SquarePants into a television series in 1996 after the cancellation of
Rocko's Modern Life, another Nickelodeon television series that Hillenburg previously directed.
As of November 28, 2025, 330 episodes of SpongeBob SquarePants
have aired, currently in its sixteenth season.
The sixteenth season consists of 13 episodes and premiered on June 27, 2025.
The SpongeBob SquarePants Movie, a feature-length film, was released in theaters
on November 19, 2004, and grossed over US$140 million worldwide.
Atlantis SquarePantis, a television film guest starring David
Bowie, debuted as part of the fifth season.
In 2009, Nickelodeon celebrated the show's tenth anniversary with Square Roots:
The Story of SpongeBob SquarePants and SpongeBob's Truth or Square.
The SpongeBob Movie: Sponge Out of Water, a stand-alone sequel, was released in
theaters on February 6, 2015, and grossed over US$324 million worldwide.
In 2019, Nickelodeon celebrated the show's twentieth anniversary with
SpongeBob's Big Birthday Blowout, a television film.
Episodes of SpongeBob SquarePants have been nominated for a variety of different awards, including 17 Annie Awards (with six wins), 17 Golden Reel Awards
(with eight wins), 15 Emmy Awards (with one win), 23 Kids' Choice Awards (with 22 wins), and four BAFTA Children's Awards (with two wins).
Several compilation DVDs have been released.
In addition, the first fifteen seasons have been released on DVD, and are
available for Regions 1, 2 and 4 as of November 11, 2025.
The tone is lighthearted and dark.